David Frederick

Front-End Developer

Phone: (409) 543-7859 Email: dfrederick79@gmail.com

6464 East Sam Houston Pkwy N, Houston, TX 77049

About

I have 5+ years of experience designing digital materials, building websites, and managing and troubleshooting software. During my most recent job, I built and redesigned 4 departmental websites for a state university and have spent extensive time practicing frontend development since then, particularly focusing on building web applications with React. I aspire to use my technological versatility, knowledge of what creates a great user experience, and adept problem-solving mindset to become a full-time Front-End/React JS Developer. My online portfolio can be viewed here: https://david-r-frederick.github.io/portfolio/

Experience

TECH SUPPORT & ADMINISTRATIVE SPECIALIST

SEP 2018 - APR 2020

Lamar University, Beaumont, TX 77705

- Completed redesign of 4 department websites using a CMS
- Designed promotional materials, flyers, and programs for 50+ biannual events
- Trained and supervised team of 4 employees

HUMAN RESOURCES ASSISTANT | SEP 2017 - SEP 2018

Lamar University, Beaumont, TX 77705

- Improved and managed the employee onboarding process of compiling hiring packets, background checks, and verifying I-9s for over 400 employees
- Entered data into HRIS for creating and altering employee records

SPANISH TEACHER | AUG 2016 - AUG 2017 Port Arthur ISD, Port Arthur, TX 77640

COMPUTER LAB ASSISTANT | SEP 2012 - MAY 2016

Lamar University, Beaumont, TX 77705

- Provided on-site Information Technology services by diagnosing and resolving software and hardware issues of department computers for students, faculty, and staff
- Oversaw technology in classrooms and the office including projectors, copiers, printers, scanners, and computers
- Delivered excellent customer service by warmly greeting visitors, actively listening to needs, and asking for clarification when necessary

CHAPLAIN ASSISTANT | FEB 2008 - MAR 2014 Texas Army National Guard, Houston, TX 77082

Education

BACHELOR OF ARTS | JAN 2011 - MAY 2016 Lamar University, Beaumont, TX 77705 Major: Psychology

Proficiencies

Programming Related: JavaScript (ES6), CSS, HTML, React, React Native, Redux, Visual Studio Code, Webpack, SQL, Bootstrap, Responsive Design

Web-based Applications: GitHub, Firebase, Cascade CMS, Formstack

Social Media: Facebook, OrgSync, Instagram, YouTube

Communication: Excellent written and verbal communication. Bilingual. Typing speed of 85 WPM.

Volunteerism

Hurricane Harvey Assistance | Beaumont, TX

Flood Relief | Deweyville, TX

Blood Donations | LifeShare Blood Center

Remodeling | Hope Clinic, Beaumont, TX

References

Will gladly furnish personal and professional references on request.